export const chapter =
  "Chapter - 24: Need for Laws and Role of the Constitution  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What gives certainty and uniformity to conduct in various activities?",
        optionA: "Personal preferences",
        optionB: "Rules",
        optionC: "Punishments",
        correctAnswer: "B) Rules",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the purpose of rules in a society?",
        optionA: "To create chaos and confusion",
        optionB: "To maintain decorum and ensure everyone's comfort",
        optionC: "To encourage rebellion and disobedience",
        correctAnswer: "B) To maintain decorum and ensure everyone's comfort",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the cricket example given, what happens when Ankur refuses to follow the rule about hitting the ball out of the park?",
        optionA: "Nothing happens; he continues to play.",
        optionB: "There is noise and argument.",
        optionC: "The game is declared invalid.",
        correctAnswer: "B) There is noise and argument.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who enforces traffic rules to ensure safe and orderly traffic flow?",
        optionA: "Local residents",
        optionB: "The government",
        optionC: "The person breaking the rule",
        correctAnswer: "B) The government",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the source of authority and power for laws in a country?",
        optionA: "The police department",
        optionB: "The legislature",
        optionC: "The judiciary",
        correctAnswer: "B) The legislature",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In what form are laws mostly found to alleviate uncertainty?",
        optionA: "Unwritten",
        optionB: "Dictated by a dictator",
        optionC: "Written",
        correctAnswer: "C) Written",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the role of the Judiciary in the legal system?",
        optionA: "Making laws",
        optionB: "Enforcing laws",
        optionC: "Interpreting and applying laws",
        correctAnswer: "C) Interpreting and applying laws",
      },
      {
        question: "How can citizens express their dissent constructively?",
        optionA: "Stage a dharna",
        optionB: "Throw objects in protest",
        optionC: "File a petition or meet with the authority",
        correctAnswer: "C) File a petition or meet with the authority",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the purpose of dissent?",
        optionA: "To create chaos",
        optionB: "To express disagreement with authority",
        optionC: "To promote destructive behavior",
        correctAnswer: "B) To express disagreement with authority",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How can people express their dissent in a constructive manner when they disagree with a law?",
        optionA: "By voting against the law in an election",
        optionB: "By taking to the streets and causing unrest",
        optionC:
          "By engaging in peaceful protests and seeking changes through democratic means",
        correctAnswer: "A) By voting against the law in an election",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Rules give certainty and uniformity to conduct, ensuring that a player or team ______ or ______. It will not be possible to decide in the absence of these rules who has won.",
        options: ["excels, improves", "wins, loses", "competes, practices"],
        correctAnswer: "wins, loses",
      },
      {
        question:
          "According to the text, a rule becomes a law when it can be enforced by the ______.",
        options: ["judiciary", "government", "community"],
        correctAnswer: "government",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Laws should be ______ by nature, which is why laws are often written down to alleviate any uncertainty about them.",
        options: ["enforceable", "certain", "flexible"],
        correctAnswer: "certain",
      },
      {
        question: "The government's power to punish rests in the ______.",
        options: ["legislature", "executive", "judiciary"],
        correctAnswer: "judiciary",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Laws provide for the maximum punishment or fine, which the judge cannot ______.",
        options: ["determine", "exceed", "ignore"],
        correctAnswer: "exceed",
      },
      {
        question:
          "An accused possesses the right to appeal to a ______ court if they are not satisfied with the judgment of the judge.",
        options: ["local", "state", "higher"],
        correctAnswer: "higher",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Constitution is the ______ of all laws in the country, and all laws must be in accordance with its provisions and spirit.",
        options: ["source", "guardian", "enforcer"],
        correctAnswer: "source",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Dissent is an important part of life, and it is expressed against the ______.",
        options: ["rules", "government", "majority"],
        correctAnswer: "government",
      },
      {
        question:
          "When dissent is expressed in a constructive manner, it should result in ______.",
        options: ["disagreement", "punishment", "agreement"],
        correctAnswer: "agreement",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The right to vote gives common people a powerful tool to express their dissent in a constructive manner during ______.",
        options: ["protests", "elections", "debates"],
        correctAnswer: "elections",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "A child is born with innate skills.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Skill development through learning by doing started during the Stone Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question: "Education and training have no impact on human development.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Trained and educated individuals are often referred to as a population burden.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Unskilled and untrained individuals contribute positively to a country's progress.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A favorable sex ratio indicates that there are more males than females in a country.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The sex ratio in India, as per the 2011 Census, was favorable.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Unfavorable sex ratios are often caused by crimes against girls and women.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A broad population pyramid at the base indicates high birth and low death rates.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Developed countries are often characterized by industrial development, leading to economic prosperity.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
